<page>
<paragraph>
    Open Access Advocacy
</paragraph>
<html>
Convincing colleagues to publish Open Access is one of the most difficult challenges for open access advocates, both new and more experienced. Here's some actions and tips to get you started, check out the <a href='https://www.openaccessbutton.org/action'>Open Access Button Action Page</a> to join the change coming to the publishing system and let us know how we can help at advocacy@openaccessbutton.org.
Here's what you can do:
</html>
<faq>
<question>
    If you have 1 minute..
</question>
<answer>
    <ul>
        <li>
            Share <a href='http://openaccessbutton.org'> openaccessbutton.org</a> on Twitter, Facebook, Google +, Tumblr (other social networking sites are available) or by email.
        </li>
        <li>
            Sign the petition in <a href='https://act.eff.org/action/let-s-stand-together-to-promote-open-access-worldwide'>support of Diego Gomez and Open Access to Research</a>.
        </li>
        <li>
            Sign the <a href='http://www.righttoresearch.org/about/statement/index.shtml'>student statement from the Right to Research Coalition</a>.
        </li>
        <li>
            Get connected by subscribing to our <a href='https://openaccessbutton.org/blog'> blog </a> or <a href='https://www.twitter.com/OA_Button'> Twitter</a> feed, or by friending us on <a href='https://www.facebook.com/openaccessbutton'>Facebook</a>. That way you'll know all the latest news and get our Action Alerts when there are exciting new opportunities for you to make a difference.
        </li>
    </ul>
</answer>
</faq>
<faq>
<question>
    If you have 10 minutes

</question>
<answer>
    <ul>
        <li>
            Talk to a friend or a colleague about Open Access, the <a href='https://www.openaccessbutton.org'>Open Access Button</a>. Try out some conversation starters like: Have you ever been asked to pay $40 to read a piece of research? or Have you ever been denied access to research you need?
        </li>
        <li>
            Use this time to bust myths (using our guides) about open access and highlight the benefits of being Open.
        </li>
        <li>
            Try to convince your colleagues who may object to Open Access to publish in an Open Access journal, Try to find out why they object to Open Access; in this app you'll find a number of resources for tackling the most common myths about Open Access.
        </li>
    </ul>
</answer>
</faq>
<faq>
<question>
    If you have 30 minutes...
</question>
<answer>
    <ul>
        <li>
            If you're a student, reach out to your professors and librarians. Reach out to them and let them know you care about open access. Send an email, grab them after class, or set up a meeting. Talk to them, ask can they publish their work Open Access or self archive existing work. Encourage your librarians to include Open Access in the mandatory library orientation for incoming students.  Use this App to bust those myths and answer those questions.
        </li>
        <li>
            Read the sections of our app to get up to speed on everything from the challenges we face in getting access to the results of research, to the impact of limited access and what you need to know about Open Access and Open Access advocacy so we can make progress on this issue together.
        </li>
        <li>
            After you've learned what we're fighting for (and why we want to change things), get connected by subscribing to our <a href='https://openaccessbutton.org/blog'>blog</a> or <a href='https://www.twitter.com/oa_button'>Twitter </a> feed, or by friending us on <a href='https://www.facebook.com/openaccessbutton'>Facebook</a>.  That way you'll know all the latest Open Access news and get our Action Alerts when there are exciting new opportunities for you to make a difference.
        </li>
    </ul>
</answer>
</faq>
<faq>
<question>
    If you have an hour...
</question>
<answer>
    <ul>
        <li>
            Write a blog/op-ed for a local newspaper. Taking your voice to a public forum can be an extremely effective form of advocacy and you all can publish anything you want with just a few clicks on a blog. If you don't have a blog, school/local newspapers are around for just this purpose—and they're often itching for content. Open access affects everybody, and an opinion piece or letter to the editor calling for change - in a few hundred words - is sure to garner interested comments or emails. If you're writing to a newspaper, let us know and we can help.
        </li>
        <li>
            Get your organisations on board. Whether you bring up the access barriers at your institution, or the heavy toll lack of access to research has on students, researchers, patients, and doctors all over the world, or something else. Lots and lots of organizations have an interest in opening up access to academic research. Let them know that access is an issue and urge them to join advocacy efforts.
        </li>
        <li>
            Get Your Faculty, Colleagues, and Administrators on board
        </li>
        <li>
            If you're a student or a researcher or a professor, spend some time working to bring them on board
        </li>
    </ul>
</answer>
</faq>
<faq>
<question>
    If you are interested in doing more...
</question>
<answer>
    For students and researchers
</answer>
<details>
    <ul>
        <li>
            If you are at an institution and it doesn't have an open access repository, advocate for one where researchers and students can deposit scholarly works.
        </li>
        <li>
            Advocate on Campus and try to implement an institutional Open Access Policy
        </li>
        <li>
            Open yourself, use our guide to help make your own work Open Access
        </li>
        <li>
            Retain your copyrights when you sign publishing agreements
        </li>
        <li>
            Serve as editor of an Open Access journal
        </li>
        <li>
            Educate your professional organizations about Open Access
        </li>
        <li>
            For more ideas, please visit <a href='http://www.earlham.edu/~peters/fos/do.htm'>this site</a>.
        </li>
    </ul>
</details>
<answer>
    For everybody
</answer>
<details>
    <ul>
        <li>
            Organize and give a talk about Open Access and the <a href='https://www.openaccessbutton.org'>Open Access Button</a>, spend some time talking to people about the Open Access Button and handing out fliers. Let us know so we can help.
        </li>
        <li>
            Get involved in International <a href='http://www.openaccessweek.org'>Open Access Week</a>
        </li>
        <li>
            Educate Locally
        </li>
        <li>
            Advocate Nationally
        </li>
        <li>
            Join Open Access Button' activism list. If you're interested, sign up <a href='https://www.openaccessbutton.org/action'>on our website</a>. or send a friendly email to advocacy@openaccessbutton.org.
        </li>
    </ul>
</details>
</faq>

<paragraph>
Further Reading
</paragraph>
<faq>
<question>
    Reading:
</question>
<details>
    <a href='http://legacy.earlham.edu/~peters/fos/brief.html'> A Very Brief Introduction to Open Access</a>, Peter Suber (and Open Access)
    <a href='http://sparceurope.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/Humanities-BP-final-PDF.pdf'>Open Access for the Humanities</a>, SPARC
    <a href='http://www.plos.org/open-access/howopenisit/'>How Open is It?</a> - PLOS
    <a href='http://legacy.earlham.edu/~peters/fos/overview.htm'>Open Access Overview</a> Peter Suber, 2004
    <a href='http://www.sparc.arl.org/issues/open-access'> Open Access</a> Scholarly Publishing and Academic Resources Coalition (SPARC)
    <a href='http://www.plosbiology.org/article/info%3Adoi/10.1371/journal.pbio.1001686'>"The Open Access Movement Grows Up: Taking Stock of a Revolution,"</a> Heather Joseph, PLOS Biology
    <a href='https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/open-access'>Peter Suber's book Open Access</a> - Available for free as an eBook or PDF
    <a href='http://oad.simmons.edu/oadwiki/Timeline'> Timeline of open access movement</a> by Peter Suber
</details>
</faq>
<faq>
<question>
    Find Open Access Resources:
</question>
<details>
    <a href='http://www.doaj.org'> Directory of Open Access Journals</a>
    <a href='http://opendoar.org/'> Directory of Open Access Repositories </a>
</details>
</faq>
<faq>
<question>
    Video:
</question>
<details>
    <a href='https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L5rVH1KGBCY'>Open Access Explained!</a> from PhD Comics
</details>
</faq>
<faq>
<question>
    Wikipedia:
</question>
<details>
    <a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_access'>Open Access</a>
    <a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creative_Commons_license'>Creative Commons Licence</a>
    <a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_access_journal'>Open Access Journal</a>
    <a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Institutional_repository'>Institutional Repository</a>
    <a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Budapest_Open_Access_Initiative'>Budapest Open Access Initiative</a>
    <a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-archiving'>Self-archiving</a>
</details>
</faq>
    </page>
